# Xiongming Dai

Ph.D. Candidate
Division of Computer Science and Engineering
Louisiana State University
Baton Rouge, LA

Email: xdai2@lsu.edu, daixiongming@gmail.com Personal Website: https://daixiongming.github.io/

Cell: (225)-228-5162

## **Research and Hobbies**

I am a Ph.D. candidate at Louisiana State University. Currently, I am working towards State Estimation for Sequential Data Analysis. I have been actively involved in various inter-disciplinary researches. I am passionate about Mathematics, Cooking, Drawing and Playing Basketball & Badminton.

## **Experience**

Graduate Research & Teaching Assistant Louisiana State University May 2018 - Present

- Responsible for theoretical research of resampling for sequential Monte Carlo, and have
  proposed a repetitive ergodicity in deterministic domain with median, it is faster than the state
  of the art, which is verified by theoretical deduction and experiments of a hidden Markov model
  in both the linear and non-linear cases.
- Responsible for theoretical research of optimal camera configuration for large-scale motion
  capture systems, a NP hard problem, and have developed a 3D simulation framework, further
  introduce Riesz potentials to discretize rectifiable submanifolds of the maximum overlapping
  coverage, it proves that the proposal grows at most logarithmically, under mild assumptions.
- Responsible for theoretical research of Monte Carlo Sampling, and have proposed a weighted Riesz potentials interaction, where only few samplers required to achieve high performance for hidden Markov model.

Director Shenzhen Realis Multimedia Technology Co.,Ltd. Jul 2016 - Aug 2017

- Responsible for the location and tracking of infrared reflective markers corresponding to rigid bodies to realize multiplayer motion capture.
- Responsible for the optimization of optimal camera configuration solutions.
- Responsible for the optimization of the inverse kinematics and the integration of the system.

Project Leader Shenzhen Realis Multimedia Technology Co.,Ltd. Feb 2016 - Jun 2016

- Served as a leader for developing inverse kinematics software from scratch.
- Responsible for the configuration and optimization of the infrared reflective markers solution so
  that the corresponding rigid body is most easily captured by the camera system.

• Responsible for the interactive communication mechanism between cameras to ensure minimum latency of the camera system.

Senior Software Development Engineer Hunan VisualTouring Technology Co., Ltd. Jun 2015 - Jan 2016

- Responsible for service robot multitasking development based on robotic systems ROS.
- Responsible for theoretical research of Visual SLAM and related software development.
- Responsible for 3D reconstruction of interior scenes.
- Responsible for 3D face recognition based on 3-dimensional projection volume invariance feature.

Software Development Engineer Huazhong Numerical Control Co., Ltd. Aug 2012 - May 2015

- Responsible for calibration research and software development of industrial robot systems.
- Responsible for the algorithm research and software development of CNC toolpaths in order to obtain smooth machining results.

#### Education

Louisiana State University Computer Science Ph.D

Publications

- Xiongming Dai, Gerald Baumgartner. Weighted Riesz Particles. Neural Information Processing Systems(NeurIPS), submitted
- Xiongming Dai, Gerald Baumgartner. Optimal Camera Configuration for Large-Scale Motion Capture Systems. Neural Information Processing Systems(NeurIPS), submitted
- Xiongming Dai, Gerald Baumgartner, Variance Reduction of Resampling for Sequential Monte Carlo. Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence(AAAI), submitted

#### **Awards**

- Three software copyright
- 2nd place in the 3rd HUST Cooking Competition
- 2012-2013 School of Mechanical Engineering at HUST 1 on 1 Basketball competition champion, called "The King of 1 on 1".
- The team got the 3rd place in the 15th HUST Graduate Cup Soccer League, Forward

• The team got the 2nd place in the 25th HUST Graduate Cup Basketball League, Small Forward

# **Technical Strengths**

- Languages Proficient: Python, R, Matlab, C/C++, Shell.
- Robotic System: ROS operating system
- GPU Programming: NVIDIA CUDA
- Computer Vision/Graphics: OpenGL, OpenCV.
- SDLC/Documentation: LaTex, Overleaf
- Platforms/ Frameworks: Windows, UNIX/Linux •
- Others: Git
- The Most Important: non-stopable and perseverance in learning

07/11/2022 updated